Part 2. You will hear a man who works for Elmley Town Council talking to some
people who want to join the small towns volunteer scheme. First you have some
time to look at questions 11 to 16.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 16.
Good morning everyone. I'm Steve Wainwright from Elmley Town Council and
I organise the town's volunteer scheme. I'm delighted you're all interested in
joining the scheme. Our volunteers help to create a sense of community among the
many people who live in our historic town of Elmley and make residents and
visitors feel welcome at local events. First I'll mention just a few of the
activities that volunteers carry out. One is to walk around the town centre
streets wearing our volunteer t-shirt. Tourists often ask how to get to a
particular shop and they might also be grateful for recommendations about what
to visit. The town holds a large number of concerts each year and part of the
volunteers role is to get everyone in the audience to the right place as
smoothly as possible. You'd be surprised how many people buy tickets then don't
check them and head for the wrong section of the hall. Volunteers may get
involved with community groups such as sports clubs or gardeners associations.
Here the volunteers talk about how groups can help each other. For instance
a writing group might want to travel to another town to hear a talk by a well
known author but may not know that another club has a coach they could
travel in. The town produces a monthly magazine and anyone who lives in the
town can send in articles. It's free to residents and is paid for by local
businesses. That's the responsibility of the council's advertising department.
We depend on volunteers though to find out what people think of events they've
attended and any suggestions they have for the future. The volunteers then send
a summary to the editors. There are a number of clubs for retired people and
every year the council arranges lunch for all the members. The volunteers
welcome the guests and when everyone's sitting down and relaxing after the meal
some volunteers put on a show. Usually around half an hour of songs and short
plays. The club members really welcome the chance to chat to the volunteers at
these events. The town council has a website of course and volunteers are
asked to help by making sure residents know about it. It's updated every day
with information about future activities and we want as many people as possible
to use it.
Before you hear the rest of the talk you have some time to look at questions 17
to 20.
Now listen and answer questions 17 to 20.
Okay now you know some of the things our volunteers do I'll go on to some
practical matters. As you probably know the town arranges three major festivals
every year and they all depend on a large number of volunteers. The book
festival lasts three days and uses several venues which all need
volunteers. More are needed for the music festival because that lasts a whole week
and even more help is required for the science festival even though it's only
two days long. It involves quite a lot of venues though. It's a good idea to help
at the festival you're most interested in because you can attend most of the
events for free. We try to use volunteers who are flexible though because some
festival events are held outdoors and the weather may affect the size of the
audience and even whether the event can take place so there can be changes at
short notice. What's essential though is being able to get on well with other
people and also to deal with someone who's behaving badly as occasionally
happens. Our plan is to get you all working in
September after a week's training starting on the 2nd so we'll be
timetabling you for duties the following week from the 9th onward. Later in the
week beginning September 23rd we have a chat with each of you to find out how
you feel about being a volunteer and what extra support you need. As a thank
you to the volunteers we arrange an annual event. In recent years we've had a
party in the Town Hall and last year a barbecue in Chamber Park. Our forthcoming
event is a trip along the canal from here to Dewhurst and back. It's on
Saturday September the 28th and if you'd like to attend you can sign up once you
start work. Now this is the volunteers t-shirt.
That is the end of part two. You now have 30 seconds to check your answers to part
two.